Hey, truckers!
We're excited to bring you the 1.60 update
for Euro Truck Simulator 2,
which is now officially released
and available on Steam.
Game Radio
With update 1.60,
we are introducing Game Radio,
a brand new in-game radio system
designed to make every drive feel
more immersive and authentic.
At launch, players can tune in to Pump It,
Rust FM,
Roadio,
Pop Gear,
and Escape.
Each station features
carefully curated tracks
hand-picked to hold up
across many hours on the road.
Escape is also a radio station designed
to help content creators
and we are committed to do our best
to keep it stream-safe.
Game Radio also introduces
a new in-game widget
displaying station info,
track titles, and artist names
while driving.
Players can customize widget behavior
through the widget option menu
by clicking F6.
Improved Material System
The Improved Material System
significantly improves the lighting
and visual quality of vehicle interiors
in selected trucks.
Its main focus is to enhance
how interior materials react to light,
which will result in a more readable,
detailed and visually pleasing
cabin environment.
One of the most significant changes
we implemented
was a redesign of the materials
used in vehicle interiors.
As a result, it makes differences
between materials such as leather,
fabric, plastic, and metal
far more apparent
even in low light conditions.
The first trucks to benefit
from the improved material systems
in Euro Truck Simulator 2
are the DAF NGD
and the MAN TGX 2020 models.
With future updates,
we will gradually add this technology
for other trucks across both games.
As part of the improved material system,
we have also carried out
minor adjustments to the global lighting.
Volvo FH Series 6 Update
With this update, truckers
will be able to customize
their Volvo FH series 6 with a selection
of several new aerodynamic parts,
including the newly designed
aerodynamic roof deflectors
available for the sleeper cab,
Globetrotter and Globetrotter XL cab variants.
Alongside these additions,
all aero cabin variants
will also have the option
to add the new distinctive black
aerodynamic A-pillar trim,
as featured on the newest
generation of Volvo FH trucks.
Job Details Widget
Based on feedback from our best community
ever and upcoming widget designs,
the Job Details widget is introduced
with the 1.60 update.
Its primary purpose is to enable a new,
more immediate and concise
way of displaying relevant job info.
Also, in response to community feedback,
the GPS will now display the estimated
arrival day and time
along with the remaining travel
time and distance.
You'll be able to enable
the Job Details Widget
through the Widget Options menu
by clicking F6.
The widget will display
key job information
including cargo type and weight,
delivery location,
job income which is color highlighted,
and the remaining time
to complete the job.
So players will have this
information available immediately
without the necessity
to pause the game.
Expanded Rest Mechanic
This new feature gives players
greater control over their rest periods
by allowing them to choose
how long they want to sleep,
and exactly when they want to wake up.
Alongside this change,
the fatigue system will now be split
into two separate values:
rest state and mandatory break.
The rest state, symbolized by a bed icon,
will now gradually deplete
rather than recover over time.
Extended periods of driving
will steadily reduce the rest state,
while resting will restore it
at a faster rate.
The mandatory brake system,
indicated by a P icon,
along with the remaining hours
before of acquired stop,
will function
more strictly.
In Euro Truck simulator 2
drivers may drive for up to ten hours
before taking a mandatory break,
which requires nine consecutive hours of rest.
Sweet dreams.
We hope that you enjoy everything
that 1.60 delivers.
To learn more about these changes,
check out the full changelog and details
at our official blog site
at blog.scssoft.com.
Oh, and don't forget
to give our socials a follow,
some of which you can find on screen now
and in the description below,
or if you're always on the road,
subscribe to our newsletter
to stay informed.
Just head to scssoft.com/newsletter
to subscribe.
Until next time.
My name's been Alex,
one of your community managers
here at SCS software,
and I'll see you on the road.